<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="master.xsl"?>
<csc:content
        xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml"
        xmlns:csc="http://castopulence.org/2010/03/content-page"
        xmlns:xsl="http://www.w3.org/1999/XSL/Transform">
    <csc:heading>News</csc:heading>
    <csc:entry id="news_entry_2">
        <csc:title>No News</csc:title>
        <csc:body>
            <p>There really hasn't been much happening as I *ahem* "we"
                have been busy with j0rbing and such. As far as
                Castopulence goes, not much has changed.</p>
            <p>The Web server host has been changed twice since the last
                update. Originally, some online acquaintances offered to
                group together on a shared dedicated server, so I *ahem*
                "we" decided to opt into that. That meant cancelling the
                original VPS (virtual private server) package.</p>
            <p>Unfortunately, my original-original VPS host
                <!--1and1-->
                ended up sucking hard and being a jerk about the whole
                thing. Basically, when I *ahem* "we" originally
                registered our domain names we had no hosting. Some
                experimentation was done from the local network using
                dynamic DNS services to map the domain names to the ever
                changing IP. Eventually, a VPS was ordered and hosting
                was moved to there. Some time later the domain names were
                transferred from the original registrar to the VPS host
                to make things simpler. Then when I wanted to cancel my
                VPS service my host <!--1and1--> told me that my
                domains were grouped into the same package as my VPS and
                cancelling my VPS would mean that I'd have to re-register
                my domains in order to keep them; <strong>even though
                they didn't expire for about a year</strong>! I don't know
                if that's even legal, but it was clear that the host
                <!--1and1--> sucked and that I *ahem*
                "we" didn't want to deal with them anymore. Since we'd
                have to pay anyway, we opted to transfer our domains to a
                new registrar. Once that was done, we cancelled our VPS
                package and moved to the shared dedicated server.</p>
            <p>Though our share of the dedicated server was no more
                expensive than our original hosting, it became clear that
                it just wasn't worth the money (no offense to the group!).
                <!--OK, I moved into my own apartment and was looking for
                ways to save money.--> All we really need right now is a
                simple, static Web server. So we decided to stop hosting
                at all for a couple of months to save some money and
                evaluate things. Then we realized that we could get a
                plenty sufficient host for a reasonable rate and here we
                are again.</p>
            <p>As far as software goes, it's hard to say just what has
                been done since the last update from Castopulence's point
                of view. There has been some minor contributions to some
                Allegro community projects. Brandon <!--Is
                referring to yourself in the third person really so
                bad?--> contributed some minor features to <a
                href="http://github.com/bamccaig/Cumulate"
                class="external">Cumulate</a>, a
                collaborative project that is itself a game: a single
                developer at a time is scheduled to add any single
                feature that they choose to the project, the goal being
                that it incrementally gets more and more complete. It was
                somewhat of an experiment, I think, and it's unfortunately
                gone stale for the moment. Somebody go contribute!</p>
            <p>The official repository for Cumulate is <a
                href="http://github.com/trezker/Cumulate"
                class="external">here</a>.</p>
            <p>Another Allegro community project, Monday, has been
                "revived" by being transferred from a private Subversion
                repository to GitHub. We never actually contributed
                anything originally, though a developer console was
                planned. Some minor work has been done to update the
                Allegro 5 bindings so it will compile with the stable
                release of Allegro 5 (the original project was started
                back in 2008 when Allegro 5 was still very unstable). It
                still needs some work in that regard. It seems a number
                of community members were happy to see it preserved so
                maybe somebody will find the time and motivation to
                continue work on it now that it's been dusted off.</p>
            <p>Some contributions were also added to another
                collaborative Allegro community project. It is intended to
                be a platform independent clipboard library. It's code can
                also be found at <a
                href="http://github.com/bamccaig/clipboard"
                class="external">GitHub</a>.
                The official repository is <a
                href="http://github.com/trezker/clipboard"
                class="external">here</a>.
                It's not very far along and somewhat of a hack, but
                eventually it might lead to something good. Last I heard
                there was some effort being put into interfacing between
                Allegro bitmaps and the clipboard.</p>
            <p>A little bit further back, a very simple animation library
                based on Allegro 4 was developed in response to a thread
                on <a href="http://www.allegro.cc"
                class="external">allegro.cc</a>. It's
                called "al4anim" and can be found on <a
                href="http://github.com/bamccaig/al4anim"
                class="external">GitHub</a>.
                A more complicated project has been started with initial
                Allegro 5 bindings. The code hasn't been fully released
                yet. It is a more abstract game framework that will
                hopefully make future game projects easier to organize and
                develop. Maybe it will even become something that the
                Allegro community can benefit from. It would be nice to
                give something more substantial back. With zero games in
                the depot it wouldn't hurt to have something to refer to.
                :P</p>
            <p>I guess that's it for now. Maybe someday soon we will find
                time to make some progress on a more serious project. Wish
                us luck!</p>
        </csc:body>
    </csc:entry>
    <csc:entry id="news_entry_1">
        <csc:title>Web Site Development</csc:title>
        <csc:body>
            <p>After a very long time sitting idle, the Web site is
                finally starting to take shape with some content.
                <tt>^_^</tt> The site is currently "static" and I'm
                debating whether or not to write scripts to modify the
                XML or to generate the XML from a database and then build
                a frontend for that. It seems the only data that
                currently can't exist in a static form is a friendly date
                representation, such as "Two hours ago", but a custom tag
                in the XML source data could provide the PHP "engine"
                with all it needs to preprocess the XML before passing it
                on to the XSL processor and ultimately the client. It's a
                WIP. We'll see what comes of it as I slowly get around to
                filling in the pages. <tt>&gt;_&gt;</tt> It would respond
                to client requests faster if the XSL output was cached,
                so that's another feature that might be implemented in
                the near future.</p>
        </csc:body>
    </csc:entry>
</csc:content>

